# **Andrew Love**

+44 (0)7785 953757

<u>love.andrew.j@gmail.com</u>

in linkedin.com/in/loveaj

o loveaj.io

London, WC1N 2LF

### **Lead Infrastructure Architect**

I am a passionate geek with an innate curiosity about using software to build better systems for business and better products for users. I have over 30 years of experience in Fintech, ranging from software development to DevOps to on-premise and cloud infrastructure. I have guided teams as the product manager for the FNZ/JHC FIGARO web, mobile and REST API product set. I have championed the use of open source software and the engagement in OSS and DevOps communities. As a partner/director I have helped create a successful Fintech company and experienced its growth phases from a start-up of 10 people to its current 250+ employees. All of this, from day one, has been done in close collaboration with clients. I have extensive experience in BA, consultant and pre-sales roles.

### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- Experienced and capable engineer
- Great communicator stakeholder audiences from user to engineer to C-Suite
- Able to take business objectives and realise them through technology and creativity
- Cross-functional and collaborative
- Open and honest approach
- Understands a wide variety of technologies and system integrations
- Public, private and hybrid cloud IaaS
- Customer/prospect-facing
- Pre-sales support
- RESTful API, mobile and web application design and development

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# Infrastructure Architect and Consultant @ FNZ/JHC Systems Ltd

2007 - 2019

Designed and implemented the infrastructure for on-premise, managed service (private cloud) and public cloud deployments of the FNZ/JHC FIGARO wealth management system. Covering networking, server specifications, 3<sup>rd</sup>-party communications, security, virtualisation, high availability, replication and disaster recovery. Directed technology reviews and upgrades to increase availability, scalability and to successfully drive down total cost of ownership.

Pioneered the development of a DevOps culture through the introduction of Ansible automation, Docker, Kubernetes container management and the integration of Ops into development projects.

Initiated and championed the provisioning of Infrastructure as Code (IaC).

Facilitated pre-sales support covering infrastructure and product integrations.

### Product Manager @ FNZ/JHC Systems Ltd

2007 - 2019

Product manager for:

- FNZ/JHC FIGARO web portal for retail & wealth management clients
- FNZ/JHC FIGARO mobile app for wealth management clients
- FNZ/JHC FIGARO REST API

Directed product vision and roadmap strategy. Guided technical/UX/UI design governance, client and market research. Negotiated and secured project funding.

#### IT Manager @ JHC Systems Ltd

2007 - 2012

Supervised all internal IT including the design and implementation of LANs, WAN, network security, data centre co-location, data backup, disaster recovery, telephony, office moves, desktop standardisation, email, document management, IBM Power Systems and vendor management.

### **SKILLS**

#### **Software Solutions & Architecture**

- Web and mobile apps
- APIs
- Distributed, complex systems and integrations
- Containers and container management systems
- Cloud-native applications (micro-services, service meshes)

#### **Software Development Life Cycle**

- Agile software development (Scrum, Kanban)
- Source control (GIT) and release strategies
- CI/CD (Jenkins)

#### Infrastructure

- Physical servers (Intel, AMD, IBM Power Systems)
- Virtualisation (VMWare, QEMU/KVM/libvirt, VirtualBox, Parallels)
- Storage (JBOD, RAID, LVM, GlusterFS)
- Networking (LAN, WAN, VPN, Software Defined Networks)
- Security (Network firewalls, application firewalls, AuthN, AuthZ)
- Operating systems (RHEL, CentOS, Ubuntu, MacOS, MS Windows, IBM i)
- Infrastructure as Code (Ansible, YAML, Terraform)

## Public, private and hybrid clouds

- Kubernetes (RedHat Openshift, GCP+GKE, KubeSpray)
- Docker, Docker Compose, Docker Swarm
- OpenStack

# Telemetry

- Loggging (Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana/Grafana, Splunk)
- Tracing (Zipkin)
- Metrics (Dropwizard, Prometheus, Grafana)
- Monitoring (Nagios, Grafana)

### **DevOps**

- Ansible
- CI/CD (Jenkins)

# Languages

- Java
- Python
- Javascript
- Bash
- HTML/CSS

### **Product Management**

- Web apps
- Mobile apps
- REST APIs

# **Client Engagement**

- On-site support and troubleshooting
- Pre-sales support and consultancy
- Software design consultancy and business analysis
- Infrastructure consultancy
- FNZ/JHC FIGARO system implementations
- FNZ/JHC FIGARO system integration projects

# **EDUCATION**

# **University of Salford**

1st BSc (Hons) Applied Physics with Electronics

# **PASSIONS**

Open Source Software (OSS) and OSS communities

Concept design

Interface design

Modern and contemporary art

Architecture (the built environment)

Science (historical and contemporary)